MOHASIN HOSSAIN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, EDUCATOR, WRITER



CONTACTS



+880 1820 937 110



hello@mohasin.dev



mohasin.dev



github.com/mohasin-dev



House# 31, Road# 1, Block# B, Aftab Nagar, Dhaka-1212, Bangladesh

SKILLS

PHP, Laravel, Lumen

MySQL, SQLite, GraphQL, MongoDB

JavaScript, jQuery, Vue.js, Vuex, Nuxt.js

React ES6, Ajax, Bootstrap, Tailwind

OOP, SOLID, KISS, DRY, YAGNI

Design Patterns, Clean Code, Refactoring

GIT, VPS Server, AWS, Linux, Docker

REST API, Payment Gateway

GIT Flow, Code Deploy

Documentation, TDD

CERTIFICATION

Diploma in Web Application Development with PHP Frameworks

Issued by: IDB-BISEW IT SCHOLARSHIP

Amazon Web services (AWS) Issued by: Udemy

EDUCATION

MSc in Zoology, 2 015 CGPA 3.24 (out of 4) Govt. Tolaram College

BS c in Zoology, 2 014 CGPA 3.32 (out of 4) Govt. Tolaram College

LANGUAGES

Bangla, English, Hindi

PROFILE

I am motivation Full stack web developer specialized in PHP, Laravel & Vue.js. I have experience in building scaling application & services in various domains. I also have experience in managing teams of developers code (Code review) and helping other developers in solving issues. I am passionate about problem-solving & collaborate techniques that helps teams grow and build better product.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Binary Fusion, Dhaka | Dec 2020 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Lead a team of three people to design and develop a highly scalable multi vendor E-commerce website with multiple payment gateway in Laravel
- Design & developed visa processing consultation system & rental management system in Laravel & Vue.js
- Customize Many Laravel, Codeignetor, PHP project of codecanyon
- Developed REST API in Laravel to assist mobile application development and other third-party integration
- Deploy projects in VPS

Feeder, Dhaka | Jan 2020 - Nov 2020

Backend Web Developer

- Collaborate with an agile team to develop features in a scalable SPA (Single Page Application) in Laravel, Vue.js & GraphQL
- Implement feedback system, weekly pdf report, Microsoft team login
- Implement Export report in Google Sheet
- Integrated slack, Microsoft team, clickup
- Developed REST API, Stripe subscriptions

Gain Solution, Dhaka | Jul 2018 - Dec 2019

Full Stack Web Developer

- Developed highly scalable software like POS, Inventory, HRM, Booking system in Laravel & Vue.js and Integrated Payment Gateway
- Developed Hospital Management System Hotel Booking, E-commerce using PHP with OOP in pure MVC pattern

PROJECT LINKS

https://feedier.com

https://grocery.binary-fusion.com

https://codecanyon.net/item/gain-pos/24209516

https://prepexcellence.stylezworld.net